Guide to the James K. Lovejoy papers, 1863-1864 MS 246
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
James K. Lovejoy papers
1863-1864
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Lovejoy, James K.
MS 246
0.1 Linear Feet (1 folder of 16 letters, 1 document)
Photocopies of letters written by Union soldier Corporal James K. Lovejoy to his wife while stationed in Louisiana, 1863-1864.
Biographical Note
Corporal James K. Lovejoy was a Union soldier. According to his death certificate, Lovejoy enlisted on August 8, 1862, at age 21, was a member of Company B, 3rd Massachusetts Calvary Regiment, and was killed in action on September 19, 1864, at Winchester, Virginia.
Scope and Contents
Photocopies of letters written by Union soldier Corporal James K. Lovejoy to his wife while stationed in Louisiana, 1863-1864. Lovejoy describes camp life, including detailed descriptions of the food and general camp conditions, and writes of his travels and adventures. The letters describe the conditions and attitudes of people both in Louisiana and the Union forces. Collection also contians a photocopy of the death certificate of James K. Lovejoy, dated July 22, 1908.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Everett Messer, Houston, Texas, July, 1975. Originals are in possession of Mrs. Everett Messer.
Index Terms
Subjects
American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865)
Document Types
corrrespondence
- Series I: Letters, 1863-1864, 16433
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from Baton Rouge, LA, March 12, 1863(?); 16449
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from Brashier(?) City, LA, April 5, 1963(?); 16448
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from Brashier(?) City, LA, May 27, 1863; 16447
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from before Port Hudson, LA, June, 23, 1863; 16446
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from before Port Hudson, LA, July 10, 1863; 16445
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from before Port Hudson, LA, August 5, 1863; 16444
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from before Port Hudson, LA, August 30, 1863; 16443
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from before Port Hudson, LA, November 10, 1863; 16442
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from before Port Hudson, LA, November(?) 1863; 16441
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from Baton Rouge, LA, December 18(?), 1863; 16440
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from Franklin, LA, March 8, 1864; 16439
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from unknown, April 15, 1864; 16438
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, Mother and Father from Alexandria, LA, May 5, 1864; 16437
  - James Lovejoy to Wife, from unknown, July 25, 1864; 16436
  - unknown to unknown(probably James Lovejoy to Wife), from unknown, letter incomplete, n.d.(1863 or 1864); 16435
  - unknown to unknown(probably James Lovejoy to Wife), from unknown, letter incomplete, n.d.(1863 or 1864); 16434
- Series II: Death certificate, 1864, 16431
  - Copy of Death Certificate for James Lovejoy, issued Boston (James Lovejoy died September 19, 1864), 16432